# HOK LEUNG YEE (KENNY)

15 Robins Wood Road Nottingham NG8 3LA

Phone: 07307080771

Email: uk.kennyyee@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/kenny852

#### **SUMMARY**

Knowledgeable systems administrator with expert technical knowledge, attention to detail and planning abilities. Diligent about following through on issues and resolving concerns for optimum system operations. Team player offering advanced technical knowledge and can-do attitude.

Certified in Microsoft® Certified IT Professional bringing 20 years of industry experience, including 7 years as System Administrator, with more than 10 years background in system administration, hardware and software troubleshooting and network management. and 20 years of technical experience in distributed network environments. In-depth understanding of business logic and flow.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress,

VPN technologies & troubleshooting, Disaster recovery planning,

Disaster recovery, Network disaster recovery,

Network repairs and maintenance,

Microsoft Server 2008, 2012, 2016, Microsoft Active Directory,

System upgrades, Performance improvements,

Network policy development, Network configuration and support,

Load balancing, Firewall policy development,

Network administration, VLAN and IP routing,

Virtual Local Area Network (VLAN), Router administration design,

IP address management, Routing protocols, Interface configuration,

Hardware installation.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### INTERNATIONAL PAPER (ASIA) LIMITED, Hong Kong

Network Specialist III

January 2018 - June 2022

- Verified system stability and integrity by conducting daily testing and monitoring.
- Maximized departmental efficiencies by creating and updating technical support documentation for systems and applications.
- Performed troubleshooting on systems and network issues.
- Consulted with management and key stakeholders to define business needs and specifications.
- Maintained broadband networks and Windows servers to enable stable operations.
- Evaluated network performance to minimize downtime through preventative maintenance and swift corrective action.
- Evaluated existing hardware and software to determine viability, ensured continuity of business by developing, testing and implementing disaster recovery plans.
- Participated in on-call shifts at certain times, including holidays and weekends in case of system or network-related emergencies.
- Participate in the users PC refresh programme, network equipment upgrade and network change implementation of network equipment in overseas branches to Japan and mainland China.
- Enabled secure network access through research and trend analysis, cutting security breaches
- Ensured all data was backed up each evening, which alleviated lost information following the malware incident.
- Maintained up-to-date software inventory, managing vendor hardware and software licensing to guarantee compliance.
- Monitored file servers and databases, improving network performance.
- Improved installation and configuration procedures to maintain stable traffic and response times.
- Managed complex networks with over 200 users, including broadband, Wi-Fi, LANs and VPNs.

#### SPORTSHOUSE LIMITED, Hong Kong

System Administrator

June 2017 - January 2018

- Tier 2 support for Office and Retail store users.
- Network monitoring, maintenance, change implementation.
- System setup, migration, monitoring, maintenance, developing patches
  & data backup.
- IT material management, procurement processing.
- Retail store stocktake manpower & resources planning.
- Site resilience project (network design & change implementation)
- Core switch firmware upgrade project.
- Lead and manage the IT support team.

#### **SWIRE RESOURCES LIMITED, Hong Kong**

System Administrator

March 2015 - June 2017

- Tier 2 support for Office and Retail store users.
- Network monitoring, maintenance, change implementation.
- System setup, migration, monitoring, maintenance, developing patches
  & data backup.
- IT material management, procurement processing.
- Retail store open/close network & system setup arrangement.
- Office internal wireless network upgrade project. (network design & change implementation)
- Core switch firmware upgrade project.
- Lead and manage the IT support team.

#### PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Microsoft® Certified IT Professional - 2013

Microsoft® Certified Solutions Associate - 2013

**Enterprise Administrator on Windows Server® 2008** - 2013

Windows Server® 2008 Applications Infrastructure, Configuration - 2012

Windows Server® 2008 Active Directory, Configuration - 2012

Windows Server® 2008 Network Infrastructure, Configuration - 2012

Microsoft® Certified Technology Specialist - 2012

Windows® 7, Configuration - 2012

Microsoft® Certified Professional - 2005

### **EDUCATION**

**Unisoft Education Center, Hong Kong** - 2005

Diploma in UNiSOFT Certified Network Expert

**Unisoft Education Center, Hong Kong** - 2004

Associate Diploma in Web Page Design

**Vocational Training Council, Hong Kong** - 2005

Certificate in IT Assistant Training Programme

HongKong And Kowloon Chiu Chow Secondary School, Hong Kong - 2005

Certificate of Graduation

## **LANGUAGES**

Cantonese, Mandarin, English, Japanese